CURRICULUM VITAE

PERSONAL DETAILS

Name: Wycliffe Mwangi Machatha

Nationality: Kenyan

ID Number: 32596719 Gender: MALE

Phone No: +254743386428

Address: P. O BOX 3900 ELDORET. Email: wmachatha@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/wycliffe-mwangi-580858137/

PROFILE

I am an experienced expert with knowledge in engineering, accounting, and project management in the solar sector. I have extensive expertise and abilities in business development as well as marketing Tier 1 solar products and projects.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To maximize my potential in a dynamic and commercial setting that makes use of my abilities and talents. As I gain new talents, I hope to make a meaningful contribution to the industry and to the leadership in my environment.

EDUCATION

JAN 2022- DEC 2023 UNIVERSITY OF EAST LONDON.

Master of Science in Data Science

Ongoing.

SEPT 2014 - DEC 2019: MOI UNIVERSITY

Bachelor's Degree in Electrical and Telecommunication Engineering Second

class honors, upper-division.

JAN 2018-NOV 2019:

Kenya institute of management studies (KIMS)

Diploma in Business project management

Upper credit division. GPA 75

MAR 2018-TO DATE: KCA University

KASNEB PROFESSIONAL EXAMS.

Certified Public Accountancy PART 2 SECTION 4 holder

JULY 2021-JULY 2021 STRATHMORE UNIVERSITY

Tier 3 Solar GRID TIED Training

FEB 2010- NOV 2013: St. Mary's boy's sec school-NYERI

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (K.C.S.E).

Mean Grade: A plain - 83 points

JAN 2002- NOV 2009: Morning starlight Academy

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education (K.C.S.E)

Score: 375 of 500

WORK HISTORY

MAY 2021-CURRENT BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER.

HEAD OF SALES DEPARTMENT.

TECHNICAL TRADING COMPANY LIMITED

- Sales, marketing, and business development
- Using the PVyst & PVCAD Toolset, prepare solar design sizing calculations and blueprints.
- Making a bill of materials for solar installations.
- Preparation of technical-commercial ideas and customer presentation pitching
- Solar financing modeling and financial payback periods calculations
- Monitoring installation and operations to ensure that stringent client criteria are met on a continuous basis.
- Commissioning and monitoring design compliance.
- Facilitated GOODWE product training and the development of GOODWE Inverter Brands to local Tier 1 EPCs.

NOV 2019- MAY 2021

SOLAR PROJECTS ENGINEER. KRYSTAL SOLUTIONS EA LIMITED

RESPONSIBILITIES

- Monitoring installation and operations to ensure that stringent client criteria are met on a constant basis. Sales, marketing, and company growth.
- PVyst / PVCAD Toolset is used to create solar design schematics.
- Energy audits and Solar PV site assessments of facilities are performed, and proposals are provided to clients.
- Solar product financing research and client advice
- Client relationship management and consulting
- Training technicians and implementing the company's safety and health rules
- Creating high and low voltage electrical equipment project plans, models, prototypes, and circuit diagrams
- Working closely with project stakeholders to identify and rapidly address challenges.
- Testing, commissioning, and end-user training are all carried out.

JULY 2019-NOV 2019 ASSISTANT SOLAR ENGINEER-KRYSTAL SOLUTIONS EA LTD

- ★ Creating system schematics using AutoCAD/PVsyst /PV CAD
- ✦ Power logging and Analysis.
- ★ Cable layout, string layout, and Earthing layout.
- + Site Management and Inventory Control on and off the site
- → Supervision
- + Ensuring Compliance with the safety and health regulations.
- + Communicating with engineers and customers on project collaboration.

APRIL 2019-JUN 2019 PLC, HMI&SCADA INTERN (INDUSTRIAL AUTOMATION)

UNGA LIMITED ELDORET

MAY 2017-AUG 2017 KPLC ENERGY TRANSMISSION ATTACHED

THIKA REGION

AFFILIATION

- → Graduate Member, Engineers Board of Kenya (EBK)
- → Licenced Solar PV Technician By Energy and Petroleum Authority to Handle All system Designs of any scale relating to Solar System and products.

RECENT PROJECTS

- Red Plum Solar System, 548KW Grid-tied Roof Mounted Solar system.
- United Industries Solar Plant-336KW Grid-tied Solar Plant
- Label Converters Industries-450KW Grid-tied Solar Plant
- Surge ENERGY-600kWp Grid-tied Solutions.
- Numerous Residential Storage systems
- Numerous Solar Pumping Systems and Water Solutions

FINTECH SOLAR PROJECTS

Wrote an award-winning KOSAP PROJECT Proposal to provide over 8000 houses in 13 underserved areas with PAYG Solar Home Kits. The World Bank provided Ksh. 35 million in funding, with SNV and SUNFUNDER serving as facility managers.

REFEREES

MOHAMED DAHIR ABDULLAHI
MANAGING DIRECTOR
VOLKS LIFT EA LTD/KRYSTAL SOLUTIONS EA
mohammed@volksliftea.com/mooamco@gmail.com
TEL: +254722333335

HARI BHOGHAITA CHIEF EXECUTIVE OFFICER, TECHNICAL TRADING COMPANY hari@ttc.co.ke TEL +254723290263

ENG. ROSE CHEMIAT, GROUP PROJECT MANAGER DAVIS AND SHIRTLIFF LTD

TEL: 0725457580

EMAIL: rchemiat@gmail.com

You can contact any of the above-named referees to attest to my character and professionalism status.